Historic New England
Bowen family papers
- Photographic material of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut, 1860-1965, undated, predominant 1860-1935; MS006.03; Photographic materials (5 file boxes, 1 folio box, 1 multi-purpose box, 1 oversize folder); Series III, Photographic material of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut, 186
  - Photographs: groups, 1866-1965, undated, predominant 1886-1898; MS006.03.02; Photographs (2 file boxes); Subseries B, Photographs: groups, 1866-1965, undated (bulk, 1886-1898) (#10.13-10.31, 11.1-11.14), contains black and white photographs, color photographs, and related letters. The subseries 
    - Bowen, Lucy Maria (Tappan) and Franklin Davis Bowen [1 photograph], undated; MS006.03.02.08 (Box 10, folder 20)
    - Bowen, Paul Holt and George McClellan [2 photographs], 1886-1889; MS006.03.02.09 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Holt, Alexina C. and John Eliot Holt [1 photograph], undated; MS006.03.02.10 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Holt, Constance; Grace Holt; and Sylvia Holt [2 photographs], 1894; MS006.03.02.11 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Holt, George Chandler and Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt: at home in Spuyten Duyvil, New York [1 photograph], undated; MS006.03.02.12 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Holt, Hamilton and Grace (Holt) Reed [1 photograph], 1877; MS006.03.02.13 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Holt, Henry Chandler and Sylvia Holt [1 photograph], 1890; MS006.03.02.14 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Holt, Mary Louisa (Bowen) and Sylvia Holt [2 photographs], 1890, undated; MS006.03.02.15 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Holt, Sylvia Holt and nurse, Henrietta [2 photographs], 1890; MS006.03.02.16 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Reed, Grace (Holt) and Lucy Richardson [1 photograph], 1897; MS006.03.02.17 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Vereker, Roxanna Wentworth (Bowen) (born 1895) and Gordon Vereker; includes letter [1 photograph], 1949; MS006.03.02.18 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Bowen family: Christmas at 90 Willow Street, Brooklyn, New York; includes Julia Ward Howe [2 photographs], 1887, undated; MS006.03.02.19; NOTE: See #11.1 and 11.3 for items removed (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Bowen family: Fourth of July celebration at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut; includes U.S. President Benjamin Harrison [3 photographs], 1887-1889; MS006.03.02.20; NOTE: Items removed from #10.31. NOTE: See #11.14 for related material. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Bowen family: Fourth of July celebration at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut; includes U.S. President Benjamin Harrison [2 photographs], 1889; MS006.03.02.21; NOTE: See #11.14 for related material (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Bowen family: Fourth of July celebration at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut; includes U.S. President William McKinley [3 photographs], 1891-1892; MS006.03.02.22; NOTE: Items removed from #10.31. NOTE: See #11.9 and 11.14 for related material. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Bowen family: Fourth of July celebration at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut [2 photographs], 1893, undated; MS006.03.02.23; NOTE: See #11.14 for related material (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Bowen family: Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut [1 photograph], 1898; MS006.03.02.24 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Bowen family: hunting party at Roseland Park, Woodstock, Connecticut; includes Nellie Chandler photographs [3 photographs], undated; MS006.03.02.25; NOTE: See #11.8 for item removed (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Bowen family: hunting party at Roseland Park, Woodstock, Connecticut [2 photographs], undated; MS006.03.02.26 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Bowen family: picnic at Roseland Park, Woodstock, Connecticut [1 photograph], undated; MS006.03.02.27; NOTE: Item removed from #11.6 for related material (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Bowen family: tea at 90 Willow Street, Brooklyn, New York; includes U.S. President William McKinley at Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut [2 photographs], 1891, undated; MS006.03.02.28; NOTE: See #11.3 for related material (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified; includes Clarence Winthrop Bowen (1852-1935), Centennial address [10 photographs], 1890-1965; MS006.03.02.29; NOTE: See #8.20 for related material (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Other photographs: William Aspinwall house on Washington Street, Brookline, Massachusetts, southwest view; includes Peter Aspinwall house, Brookline, Massachusetts [4 photographs], 1867, undated; MS006.03.02.30 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Other photographs: Bowen family residence at 90 Willow Street, Brooklyn, New York [1 of 2] [4 photographs], undated; MS006.03.02.31 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Other photographs: Bowen family residence at 90 Willow Street, Brooklyn, New York [2 of 2] [8 photographs], undated; MS006.03.02.32 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Other photographs: Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut; includes U.S. flag and Herbert Wolcott Bowen house, Woodstock, Connecticut [15 photographs], 1952-1959, undated; MS006.03.02.33; NOTE: See #11.1-11.4 for related material (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Tintypes, 1872-1875, undated; MS006.03.03; Tintypes (1 file box); Subseries C, Tintypes, 1872-1875, undated (#12.1-12.14), contains tintypes of Bowen family members and is divided into two categories: portraits and groups. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by surname, first by portraits, then by groups; when applicable, women are identified by married name. (HGO-02-105-A-E-302)
    - Portraits, 1872-1873, undated; MS006.03.03.01; Tintypes (5 folders)
      - Barney, Susan E. (Tappan) (dates unknown) [2 items], undated; MS006.03.03.01.01 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Bowen, Clarence Winthrop (1852-1935) [1 item], undated; MS006.03.03.01.02 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Holt, Hamilton (1872-1951) [1 item], 1872-1873; MS006.03.03.01.03 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Holt, Mary Louisa (Bowen) (1848-1925) [5 items], undated; MS006.03.03.01.04 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Hulett, [Don A. or Lewis Tappan] [1 item], undated; MS006.03.03.01.05 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Groups, 1872-1875, undated; MS006.03.03.02; Tintypes (9 folders)
      - Barney, Susan E. (Tappan) and family [1 item], undated; MS006.03.03.02.01 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Bowen, Clarence Winthrop; Edward Augustus Bowen; [Henry Elliot Bowen or George Chandler Holt] [1 item], undated; MS006.03.03.02.02 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Bowen, Edward Augustus; Grace Aspinwall (Bowen) Hardy; Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt; and Alice L. (Bowen) Richardson [1 item], undated; MS006.03.03.02.03 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Hardy, Grace Aspinwall (Bowen); Hamilton Holt; and Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt [2 items], 1872-1873; MS006.03.03.02.04 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Holt, George Chandler and Hamilton Holt [2 items], 1872-1873; MS006.03.03.02.05 (Box 12, Foler 10)
      - Holt, George Chandler; Hamilton Holt; and Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt [1 item], undated; MS006.03.03.02.06 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Holt, George Chandler and Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt [2 items], undated; MS006.03.03.02.07 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Holt, Hamilton and Mary Louisa (Bowen) Holt [1 item], 1872-1873; MS006.03.03.02.08 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Hulett, Margaret and J.A. Tappan [1 item], 1875; MS006.03.03.02.09 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Photograph albums, 1860-1880, undated; MS006.03.04; Photograph albums (1 folio box, 1 multi-purpose box); Subseries D, Photograph albums, 1860-1881, undated (#FB.2.1, MB.1.1-MB.1.2), contains three photograph albums. The Bowen, Barney, and Holt family album (#FB.2.1) is comprised of approximately one hundred black and white cabinet size and carte de visite photographs. The album contains photographs of Bowen family members, friends, and celebrities (including military heroes such as U.S. Generals John Charles Fremont, 1813-1890 and Winfield Scott, 1786-1866; and a collage of U.S. Generals: Anderson, Banks, Butler, Dix, Fremont, Lyon, McClellan, Scott, and Wool). Also included are a photograph of Edward Augustus Bowen's (1847-1926) horse, Ruby; Hiram Barney's (dates unknown) house, Cedar Knolls, located at Spuyten Duyvil, New York; and friends of Edward A. Barney (dates unknown) from the Eastman School in Poughkeepsie, New York (including a group playing polo). The Bowen, Barney, and Tappan family album (#MB.1.1) is comprised of approximately thirty-nine black and white carte de visite photographs. The album contains portraits of Bowen family members, Bowen friends, and celebrities. Also included is a photograph of the Bowen family governess, Edna Dean Proctor (1829-1923); a photograph of Grace Aspinwall (Bowen) Hardy (1850-1940) with her doll, Lena Rivers, which is held by Historic New England; carte de visite photographs of poet Elizabeth Barrett Browning (1806-1861); a cartoon of a child receiving a haircut; and a carte de visite of "Mother and Child" with the poem "Motherless Child" by John Greenleaf Whittier (1807-1892). The Holt family album (#MB.1.2) is comprised of approximately twenty-six black and white carte de visite photographs. The album contains portraits of Holt family members; most are of children. Also included is an 1877 photograph of Grace (Holt) Reed (1874-1937) with several of her dolls taken on February 8. (HGO-02-105-A-E-101)
    - Album: Bowen, Barney, and Holt families [100 items], 1860-1880; MS006.03.04.01; NOTE: See also #10.16 for related material (Box FB.2, Item 1)
    - Album: Bowen, Barney, and Tappan families [39 items], undated; MS006.03.04.02 (Box MB.1, Item 1)
    - Album: Holt family [26 items], 1873-1877; MS006.03.04.03 (Box MB.1, Item 2)
  - Photographs on paper, portraits, MS006.03.12.01; 26 folders (82 items); The majority of this series is comprised of portraits of members of the Bowen, Holt, Richardson, and Tappan families, in addition to a small number of unknown or unrelated persons. Most of these photographs are undated.
  - Photographs on paper, groups, 1846-1965, MS006.03.12.02; 15 folders (32 items); This series includes group portraits of members of the Bowen and Holt families, as well as some unknown or unrelated persons. Most of these photographs are undated.
    - Group portrait of seven men, seated, facing front, on the porch, Roseland Cottage, Woodstock, Connecticut, 1892, MS006.03.12.02.003; The men are identified on the verso as: Senator Platt, Attorney General Miller, Secretary Tracy, Elliott F. Shepard, Senator Frye, J.P. Morgan, Commissioner for the Indians, Henry Chandler Bowen.
  - Photographs on paper, architecture, 1855, ca. 1855; MS006.03.12.03; 2 folders (6 items); This series includes photographs of the Aspinwall House and Roseland Cottage. These photographs are undated.
  - Photographs on paper, scenery, MS006.03.12.04; 0 items
  - Tintypes, portraits, 1850-1900, MS006.03.12.05; 5 folders (10 items); This series includes tintypes of members of the Tappan, Bowen, and Holt families. These photographs are undated.
  - Tintypes, groups, 1870-1900, MS006.03.12.06; 9 folders (12 items); This series includes tintypes of members of the Tappan, Bowen, and Holt families photographed in groups. Most of these photographs are undated.
  - Miscellany, undated, MS006.03.12.07; 4 folders (approx. 20 items); This series includes Anna Mellon's recollections of the interior furnishings of the rooms at Roseland Cottage, newspaper clippings related to Roseland Cottage and its residents, photographs of paintings at Roseland Cottage and miscellaneous bills related to its construction.
- Additional papers of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut, MS006.04; Family papers: 4.25 linear ft. - unprocessed (3 cartons, 3 file boxes), plus 1 folio box, and 1 oversize box; Series IV, Additional papers of the Bowen family of Woodstock, Connecticut (unprocessed), contains material purchased by Historic New England from Hamilton Holt (1872-1951) in 2005, which will be processed at a later date.
- Temporary, MS006.TMP